

Soma Utsumi

Platform Engineer

- Tokyo, Japan
- qithub.com/soma00333
- soma00333.notion.site/Soma-Utsumi-32fff212315a4e9d894b704d52b23074

SUMMARY

I'm a Senior Software Engineer with 6+ years of experience and a Platform Engineer with 2+ years of professional experience in Tokyo, Japan.

I engaged in the backend developments for enterprise SaaS and the operation of cloud infrastructures with high-security requirements.

I am good at developments using go and gRPC and operating infrastructures using GKE.

SKILLS

SRE

- SLI/SLO
- Datadog
- · Capacity Planning
- Incident Management
- Security

Platform Engineer

- GCP
- Kubernetes
- Terraform
- · Architectural Design
- Developer Experience

Backend

- Go
- gRPC
- PostgreSQL
- Microservice

LANGUAGES

- Japanese(Native)
- English(Business)

WORK EXPERIENCE

2024-04 -

Freelance, Embedded SRE in AI/LLM Division

Present

LayerX Inc.

- I conducted a performance test to determine where to deploy the enterprise
- I deployed infrastructure to the enterprise client's environments using the closed network

2023-11 -

Freelance, Enabling SRE/Platform Engineer

Present

enechain Corporation

- I created manifest and terraform generator tools for developers that accelerate microservice development.
- I rebuilt the Terraform infrastructures to improve execution speed and cost efficiency.
- I unified the technology stack and standardized microservices architecture.
- I standardized repository structures and branch strategies for manifest and terraform.
- I standardized how to use Datadog APM and service map.
- I introduced telepresence to the dev cluster to improve the developer experience.
- I redesigned the access control policies with high governance and security standards.

2023-08 -

Freelance, Infra Engineer in LLM STUDIO Division

2024-04

Algomatic Inc.

- I created the learning infrastructure for LLM.
- I deployed the inference server using LLM of billions of parameters.
- I deployed infrastructures for the LLM application.

2019-04 -

CTO/Enabling SRE

Present

Industry Technology Inc.

- I developed the backend of the enterprise SaaS consisting of over 60 services.
- I deployed application infrastructures that ensured enterprise security and governance standards.
- I migrated legacy Aurora Serverless v1 (MySQL 5.7) to Aurora Serverless v2 (MySQL v8.0) without downtime.
- I designed SLI/SLO and created dashboards and monitors on Datadog.
- I migrated from a modular monolith to microservices with no downtime.

EDUCATION

2014 - 2018

Bachelor of Engineering

The University of Tokyo

 I designed a preoperative evaluation system for elderly patients using a generalized linear model.